the question is, if Estonia is in the European Union, then
вопрос если ш Эстония в Евросоюзе да то
Skoda Octavia when it is transported from the European Union
Skoda Octavia когда ведётся из Евросоюза
through Kazakhstan to Russia, it
через Казахстан в Россию она в России
will become more expensive in Russia than in Estonia, look, it
дороже станет чем в Эстонии смотрите это
works a little differently,
немного не так работает
I
я
Hello Hello, where are you from
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы откуда
Roslov Rostov I understand I IP Pärnu
Рослов Ростов надону понял я ИС Пярну
is where Estonia is and Rostov is nanu  This is
это где Эстония а Ростов нану Это
where Russia understood Well, you never know Listen that
где Россия понял Ну мало ли Слушай что
such an outfit of roulette Rubaki is such a
такой наряд рулетки Рубаки такой я
deputy and that of the city council Well, I
депутат и что городского совета Ну я
always go like this in
всегда так хожу в
a shirt Pony I’m at my workplace
рубашечка Поня Я на рабочем месте у себя
like, well, well, such a
типа ну что ну такой
deputy there in Estonia installed a
себе депутат там Эстонии поставил
Ukrainian VPN with a Ukrainian flag I  I’m
украинский ВПН с украински флагом Я же
not yours, yes, I’ve been talking to Ukraine for
не Ваш ан Да Я я с Украиной разговаривал
2 hours, I’m just now talking to Russia.
2 часа только что сейчас с Россией
Yes, well, that’s not true. The entrance
говорю Да и что ну это ж не так Летка
shows that you’re from Ukraine. Well,
показывает что вы с Украины Ну потому
because I have a Ukrainian VPN. I, I
что у меня VPN украинский стоит Я же Я
chose Ukraine, I put Ukraine, I
же выбирал Украину ставил Украину
talked to  Ukraine Well, well, to
общался с Украиной Ну что Ну чтобы
communicate with Ukraine you don’t need to install a
общаться с Украиной вам не надо ставить
VPN, just install opponents from Ukraine
ВПН просто ставить оппонентов из Украины
no no, that doesn’t work because
нет нет так не получается потому что они
then they don’t choose, look if I’m from
тогда не выбирают смотрите если я из
Estonia. Look, there’s no option in chat
Эстонии Вот Вы посмотрите нету в чат
roulette. Look, you
рулетке возможности Вот посмотрите вы не
can’t choose an opponent from  Estonia, if
можете выбрать оппонента из Эстонии если
I put Ukraine or Russia there, I don’t
я ставлю там Украина или Россия я не
get with it because they don’t choose
попадаю с им потому что они не выбирают
Estonia, I put Poland and the Poles
эстони ставил Польшу и мне поляки
got me Poland, yes, because Estonia
попадали Польша да потому что а Эстонии
is not on chatroulette Latvia Lithuania is, but
нету в чатрулетке Латвия Литва есть а
our Estonia is not there And that’s all then
Эстонии нашей нет А всё всё тогда
There are no questions if you don’t  gender Yes, and I
Вопросов нет если вам нет полу Да и мне
need to put another country so that
нужно поставить другую страну чтобы
I come across people from different countries. I
попадались мне люди из разных стран Я
put Ukraine and I come across both
ставлю Украину и мне попадаются и
Ukrainians and Russians because they choose
украинцы и русские потому что выбирают
this country. It’s clear
эту страну Понятненько а
what interests you in
что вас интересно в
Ukraine in Estonia, the city of
Украине в Эстонии город
RNU. Well, they showed
РНУ Ну выставили
Ukraine that I don’t quite trust
Украин том что я не совсем доверяю
news that goth That’s why I communicate with
новостям которые гот Я поэтому общаюсь с
Ukrainians and Russians to understand what’s
украинцами с россиянами чтобы понять что
going on. I do this once a month. I go out to
происходит Я раз в месяц так Выхожу в
chat roulette to talk with these
чат рулетку поговорить с этими
peoples. You understand
народами понимаете
SNF from
снф из
Like you, for example, here with the Russians, have
Как у Вас например вот у Россиян
your prices increased or not
повысились ли у вас цены или не
increased? answer this question like this
повысились ответить на этот вопрос так
answer yes, well, by segments, that is, let
отвечайте да да ну по сегментам то есть
’s say Well, for the entire time Well, over the
допустим Ну вот за всё время Ну вот за
last 2 years, maybe even 3 years,
последние 2 года даже может даже 3 года
gasoline is acceptable, the second day if we take it
бензин допустим дено второй если возьмём
there Yes, it increased somewhere from 43 rubles to
там Да он повысился где-то с 43 руб до
50, now the price is 50, that is,
50 вот сечас цена 50 то есть
insignificant  increase Well, not almost
незначительное повышение Ну как не почти
20% Well, well, it’s not
20% Вот ну как бы не
much Yes, it feels like there
сильно Да по ощущениям то есть вот вот
was an increase, remember there were hysterics,
было повышение помните были истерики у
we will have there that there are already 200 rubles for a
нас появится там что там уже 200 руб за
dozen, that is, it’s like that, yes
десяток то есть вот такое как бы да вот
now there’s a rebound to 90 rubles Well  this is already in
сейчас отскок до 90 руб Ну это уже в
such a normal mode, a rebound is already a
таком обычном режим отскок это уже
rebound, damn it cost about 75 before that, that
отскок блин стоили до этого где-то 75 то
is, let’s say, before this breakthrough, that
есть допустим да до вот этого рывка то
is, then up to 200, then they removed the customs
есть потом до 200 потом сняли таможенные
duty on a cart of well, eggs, that is, let’s say
пошин на воз ну э яиц то есть допустим
they were driven abroad mainly with
их погнали за границей в основном с
Turkey, that is, yes, somewhere there they lowered it
Турцию то есть да э там где-то опустили
to 130, as if now everything was returned as
до 130 как бы сейчас уже всё вернули Как
before, that is, I don’t know what
как прежде то есть не знаю с чем связан
this crisis was connected with, that is, just now the
был этот кризис то есть вот вот сейчас
last time I went to the store there was 90
последний раз заходил в магазин там 90
Yes, that’s a communal apartment Well, damn percent
Да вот э коммуналка Ну блин процентов на
rose by 5-7 Here they keep her,
5-7 поднялась Вот её
that is, electricity is 4 rubles somewhere, that
то есть электричество 4 по руб где-то то
is, well, I have even less I just
есть ну меня ещ меньше У меня просто в
don’t have gas in the apartment, that is, if there is no
квартире газа нет то есть если нет
gas in the apartment, there is a tariff itto
квартире газа там й тариф итто
27 Well, if there is gas, there is And how much is
27 Ну если есть газ есть А сколько
the salary  now in Russia because I’m
зарплаты сейчас в России потому что я
the minimum wage for you 19,000 rubles well, look, in
минималка вас 19000 руб ну смотрите на
fact, I don’t understand
самом деле как бы я вообще не понимаю
what’s going on
что происходит
Duma at all. In short, I’m from Rostov, that is.
Дума Короче я с Ростова надану то есть
Therefore, I can speak more or less for my
Поэтому могу сказать более-менее за свой
region, and then again, I get information
регион и то я опять же черпаю информацию
from social networks because  that they won’t And
из соцсетей потому что не будут А у тебя
how much is your salary? I’ll now multiply and
сколько зарплата я сейчас множ сложу и
multiply the shadow economy,
перемножь теневой экономики реальную
we probably won’t
зарплату наверно мы не
know the real salary from Rostov
узнаем по Ростову надону
Yes, the median salary in Rostov will need
Да медианная зарплата в Ростове надону
2023 46,000 rubles no nonsense,
2023 год 46.000 руб нет глупости вот
just now I was looking at
только сейчас смотрел в телеграме
the news on telegram, look, look at the median
новости посмотри посмотри медианная
salary right here  now look like this
зарплата вот прямо сейчас так смотрите
So a lot has changed for us, I don’t know what happened in
Так у нас много изменилось я не знаю что
2003 and somehow, the
там 2003 году и как то есть вот
last time I looked at the news
последний раз который смотрел новостную
feed, that is, the salary in Rostov
ленту то есть зарплата в Ростове
rose to 70,000 rubles. That is,
поднялась до 70.000 руб То есть у нас
everything went up in this part for us once again once
всё поднялось в этой части ещё раз ещё
again  look
раз ещё раз смотри
no look the average average salary is
нет смотри средняя средняя зарплата
66,000 rubles yes and the median is 46 How how What is the
66.000 руб да а медианная 46 Как как Чем
difference between the average and the median you
отличается средняя от медианной
understand I understand before paying taxes you
понимаете Я понял до уплаты налогов вы
have no no no look I’ll explain
име нет нет не то смотрите объясню
For example,
Например
if 100 people receive
если 100 человек получает
one ruble each And one receives a billion
по одному рублю А один получает миллиард
Yes the average will be
Да средня будет там
100,000  Yes, it seems like the average is 100,000 But this one
100.000 Да вроде средня 100.000 Но это о
receives a billion and the rest is a ruble
получает миллиард а остальные по рублю
median - This is when all
медианная - Это когда берутся все
salaries are taken, 10 single billion are written out
зарплаты выписываются вот 10 единичен
and the median is in the middle, that
млрд и медианная - это посередине то
is, the median - This means that half of
есть медиана - Это значит что половина
the population of Rostov receives no more than
населения Ростова получает не больше
46,000 rubles, I understand that is stagnant  well, that
46.000 руб я понял то есть засти ну э
means I looked at the average salary there and it
значит я смотрел среднюю зарплату там да
went up to 70, but I can tell you
поднялась до 70 но я вам могу сказать
that for 40,000 you won’t force anyone to
что за 40.000 вы никого не заставите
work here. Personnel shortage is everywhere
работать тут Кадровый голод повсюду ещё
again, I don’t know whether they will force you or not,
раз я не знаю заставят или не заставят
but your official media, yes, the
но Медиа официальные ваши да
median salary is 46,000 rubles, that is,
медианная зарплата 46000 руб то есть
half  Now I’m wondering
половина вот сейчас мне интересно
how much a doctor, for example, or a teacher,
сколько врач например или там учитель
now listen better doctor because
сейчас слушайте лучше врач потому что
we
бедных врачей у нас
don’t have poor doctors and their salaries will be so
нет а зарплата уних будет быть поэтому
you So look, that’s why you
вы Поэтому вот смотрите Вы же поэтому
went to chat roulette, they said that is, well, I
зашли в чат рулетку сказали то есть ну я
don’t trust the Internet resources there, yes
не доверяю интернет-ресурсам там да
so I’m asking personally, that is, let’s say,
поэтому спрашиваю лично то есть допустим
so I’m telling you how it really
поэтому я вам говорю как оно реально
is, that is, let’s say, in general, nothing with
обстоит то есть допустим вообще ниру с
what the state is showing. If you
тем что показывает государство Если вы
now ask about teachers, I don’t
сейчас Спросите по поводу учителей не
know, but about doctors, that is, yes, here’s
знаю но по поводу врачей то есть да вот
probably a teacher. Here in Rostov, in Rosto, there’s a
навер учитель Вот в Ростов в Росто
Russian teacher  language 45 50,000
учитель русского языка 45 50.000
rubles can be useful because they
руб может быть кстати потому что они
work, by and large, they
работают по большому
receive a salary in the summer they don’t
счёту зарплату получают летом не
work,
работают
you don’t know again No, I don’t know how
вы не в курсе ещё раз Нет не в курсе как
teachers look, this is also a
учителя смо смотрите это ещё это ещё
high salary, in fact, I’m
высокая зарплата на самом деле как бы я
surprised who goes to these  these
удивлялся Кто идёт на эти вот эти
budget positions for teachers, that
бюджетные должности преподавателей да то
is, the salary is not high and many had
есть зарплата не высокая и у многих был
such a motive, here I am with one teacher
такой мотив вот я с одной преподавателем
by chance, listen, I
случаю гово Слушайте я вот в первой
worked the first shift and went home
смене отработала и пошла домой
to do my own thing, summer has come.
заниматься своими делами лето наступило
That is, I’m going to the sea for a month, that
То есть я на месяц на море уезжаю то
is, let’s say  there she spent it once on the road, got a
есть допустим там на дорогу один раз
job somewhere
потратила там пристроилась где-то
cheaper and so on, it’s just a way of
подешевле и так далее просто это образ
life,
жизни
that’s
вот
a plus Well, let’s still say. For me,
плюс Ну и всё равно допустим Для меня
this motivation is unacceptable, that is, let’s
эта мотивация неприемлема то есть да
say that she just works there for half a day
допустим что просто там полдня
and that’s why she agrees to
поработать и поэтому она согласна на
some kind of minimum wage then  there is, let’s say,
какую-то минималку то есть допустим
which is paid in Russia, that is, yes,
которую платится в России то есть да вот
well, this is most often a choice. In this
ну это чаще всего вот выбор В этом
direction, as for Now you
направлении что касается Вот вы сейчас
will open doctors there I don’t think that
откроете врачей там Я не думаю что ещё
once again I don’t understand why, look
раз ещё раз ещё раз я не понял смотрите
why For example, in Estonia there is a teacher
почему Например в Эстонии учительница
who also works half a day  also
которая также работает полдня также
has a month of vacation like everyone else Yes in uh
имеет месяц отпуска как и все Да во э
salary uh minimum salary we have
зарплата ээ минимальная зарплата у нас
800 euros average What uh minimum salary
800 евро средняя Какая ээ минимальная
800 euros I say median now let
800 евро я говорю медианная сейчас
's see let's
посмотрим давайте я сейчас точно
look at the median now for sure Because I don't
посмотрю медиану Потому что я не
know 1.300 euros I'll tell you so now
знаю 1.300 евро я вам так скажу сейчас
well the median is not  I know, I’m telling you the average
ну медиана не знаю я среднюю говорю вам
1,300 that’s how the median salary is 1,600
1.300 вот так медианная зарплата 1.600
1,600 euros So listen, I opened it
1.600 евро Так слушайте я открывал
recently, that is, let’s say, and not stop stop stop stop stop stop stop stop stop
недавно то есть допустим а не стоп стоп
stop
стоп стоп стоп стоп стоп стоп стоп стоп
second
секунду
like that No median 800 euros 800 euros and the
так Нет медианная 800 еввро 800 евро а
average Now let’s see you wanted the
средняя Сейчас посмотрим вы хотели
average
среднюю
1.200 1.3  it will be like this average salary
1.200 1.3 будет так средняя зарплата
2,700 euros average 2 no stop
2.700 евро средняя 2 нет стоп Вот вот
Look again stop in the second quart
ещё раз смотри стоп во втором кварта
wait not in the second to not in the median
подожди не во втором к не во медианная
1,600 euros average 2,000 euros
1.600 евро средняя 2.000 евро
is the minimum wage 800 euros
это минималка 800 евро
Yes And I opened the statistics looked 1,300
Да А я открывал статистику смотрел 1.300
euros and I came across the same Latvians
евро и мне попадались такие же латыши
who said again, well, look
которые говорили ещё раз ну посмотри вот
now, look, I, in order to
сейчас смотри я я для того чтобы
look, I know that we have a minimum wage, yes. I
посмотреть я знаю что минималка у нас да
look again, look like this, here’s the
Я вот ещё раз по смотрите вот так вот
official
официальный
website, so in the second in the second quarter of
сайт так во втором во втором квартале
2024, the average salary in Estonia
2024 года средняя зарплата в Эстонии
was 2.7 euros, the median salary  41
составила 2.7 евро медианная зарплата 41
euros official
евро официальные
data is false That is, I watched or
данные лживые То есть я смотрел либо
listen to Latvia Well,
Латвию слушайте Ну если вот 2.000 Евро
if you already earn 2,000 Euros there If you are on
там уже зарабатывать Если ты будешь на
this tape at the factory There Volkswagen
этой ленте на заводе Там Volkswagen по
again look again look
ещё раз смотри ещё раз смотри
we only earn money again we
мы лько зарабатывает ещё раз мы мы
look Yes, you are not average and  we
смотрим Да вы не среднюю и эту мы
compared this one in Rostov, the
сравнили в Ростове
average is 66,000, this is 660
средняя 66.000 это 660
in Media PP is not average 2000 average is 2000
у Медиа ПП не средняя 2000 средняя 2000
dollars, our average is three times more
долларов средняя у нас больше в три раза
than yours, I understood in short, the
чем у вас я понял короче е
purchasing power should be considered the
покупательскую способность надо считать
purchasing power that ione ione is
покупательская способность что ione ione
cheaper in Estonia Yes, a car is cheaper to
в Эстонии дешевле Да автомобиль дешевле
drink and gasoline  you have to drink every day Let's
поть а бензинчик надо каждый день пить
see
Давайте
in Russia or in Estonia, let's give
см Росси или в Эстонии давайте давайте в
three times more
Эстонии в три раза больше
salary in Estonia Show me which car
зарплаты Покажите какой автомобиль
again which one I don't know how much is
в ещё раз какой я не знаю сколько шда
left Let's see now How much does it
оста Давайте Сейчас посм Сколько у вас
cost you listen Well, he doesn't officially
стоит слушайте Ну он их официально не
import them, it's with everyone there  gaskets, that
завозит это со всеми там прокладками то
is, it now costs somewhere Well, more than 3
есть она сейчас стоит где-то Ну больше 3
ml rubles, it
мл руб
's somewhere, it's more than 30 from
это это где-то это больше 30 откуда
Where do they get Octavia straight away through
Откуда заводят сходу Октавии через
Kazakhstan, oh well, from where From what countries from the
Казахстан э ну откуда С каких стран с
European Union Yes yes yes from the European Union Kazakhstan
Евросоюза Да да да с Евросоюза Казахстан
Caste question Yes question If school Estonia
Каста вопрос Да вопрос Если шко Эстония
in the European Union, yes, then Skoda Octavia when it
в Евросоюзе да то Skoda Octavia когда
is transported from the European Union through Kazakhstan to
ведётся из Евросоюза через Казахстан в
Russia, it will become more expensive in Russia than in
Россию она в России дороже станет чем в
Estonia, look, it works a little differently.
Эстонии смотрите это немного не так
When I was in the Czech Republic, look.
работает Я когда был в Чехии смотрите Я
When I was in the Czech Republic, yes, I was
когда был в Чехии Да я вот специально
there specifically in the neighboring city from Prague 30  km Where are
там в соседний город от Праги 30 км Где
Octavias assembled It would seem that is, yes,
собирают Октавии Казалось бы то есть да
at that moment when I stopped by, I
на тот момент на тот момент когда заехал
think I went straight into the salon, I think
думаю я прямо в салон зашёл думаю
I’ll see how much a set like mine
погляжу сколько такая застави как у меня
costs, and in the Czech Republic where it is
комплектации стоит и в Чехии где её
assembled, it cost more than in Russia, it’s
собирают она стоила дороже чем в России
terrible, I understand correctly  that uh,
ужас получает я правильно понимаю что ээ
the seller who takes the car in the Czech Republic
продавец который берёт в Чехии
takes it to Russia pays the duty
автомобиль везёт в Россию платит пошлину
Yes, by weight, everything is uh and the car becomes
Да на вес так всё э и автомобиль стаёт
cheaper in Russia
дешевле в России
Yes Listen, you are a deputy, as well as once again,
Да Слушайте вы депутат как и ещё раз ещё
I just can’t understand this
раз я просто не могу понять вот эту
tax scheme, look, there are taxes on
схему нало на смотрите есть же налоги на
the sale of the correct internal country,
продажу правильно внутренней страны
which may be higher than in Russia, that
которые могут быть выше чем в России то
is, yes, let’s say Well, there is something when
есть да допустим Ну есть е что э когда
you send it for export. You return VAT there, that
ты на экспорт отправляешь Ты там НДС
is, yes, so again, don’t
возвращаешь то есть да так ещё раз не
just explain to me, explain to me,
вот просто объясните мне объясните мне
really really bought what you sold it for. Here
реально реально купил за что продал Вот
you are  say No no a hundred Where did you buy and sell
вы говорите Не нет сто Где купил продал
more Show me really, I want to
ещё Покажите мне реально вот я хочу
see yes Where in Russia is the Skoda Octavia Yes, the
увидеть да Где в России Skoda Octavia Да
same configuration as in the Czech Republic
такой же комплектации как в Чехии
will be cheaper, it’s just real you will
дешевле будет вот просто реально вы
now receive the Nobel Prize in
сейчас получите Нобелевскую премию по
Economics really right now I’m
экономике реально прямо сейчас я вас
mining you look at 14 or  PM year, I
минирую смотрите в 14м или ПМ году я
just bought an Octavia and I was in the Czech Republic and I
только купил Октавию и я был в Чехии и я
went into the salon, I was still surprised, I think, How is it
зашёл в салон я ещё удивился думаю Как
possible that in the Czech Republic salon it
такое возможно что в салоне Чехии она
costs less than here? But there is one
стоит дешевле чем у нас Но есть один
nuance that the Octavia was assembled in Kaluga at that
нюанси октави собиралась в Калуге на тот
time
момент
from exactly the same
из из точно таких же
capita  listen Well, you are not a deputy, you are
капиту слушайте Ну вы не депутат вы вы
already forgiven, the question is not for me, I’m just interested,
уже проща вопро не мне просто интересно
I just look, I’m just surprised, I’m a
Я просто смотрите я просто удивляюсь я
deputy Yes, in the city of Pärnu, but when they
депутат Да в городе Пярну но меня когда
say that a car from the European Union
говорят что автомобиль из Евросоюза
is brought to Russia and it becomes
приводят привозят в Россию и он стаёт
cheaper, it’s just nonsense, really cool
дешевле это просто нонсенс реально круто
You have  I'll tell you about negative duties,
У вас у вас я по отрицательные пошлины
that is, when they transport you, they also pay extra Yes, look at the
то есть когда возят ещё доплачивают Да
price, look at it Let's
цена смотрите вот смотрите Давайте
compare the prices of a new car of the
сравним цены нового автомобиля одной и
same brand Well, since you
той же марке Ну раз интернетом
use the Internet in Russia and Israel, a
воспользуетесь в России и в Израиле
country friendly to Europe, again,
дружественной Европе стране ещё раз
look at Israel. I live in Estonia.
причём Израиль смотрите Я живу в Эстонии
You live in  Russia, we
Вы живёте в России вот у нас граница
have a border So Narva Let's now actually
есть Так Нарва Давай сейчас фактически
talk about the standard of living You now
заговорили про уровень жизни вы сейчас
start comparing the moments that are convenient for you
начинайте сравнивать удобные вам моменты
This is what this is what you have there What
вот это что вот это то что у вас там что
stop is not this You want convenient You
стоп нет это вы хотите удобно Вы же
said Let's have gasoline I said yes
сказали Давайте бензин Я же сказал да
let's for  so that gasoline first the
давайте для того чтобы бензин сначала
car and you feel inconvenienced why
машину и Вам неудобно стало почему
mandatory payments like it or not
обязательные платежи хочешь не хочешь
you don’t have to buy the car wait
машину ты можешь не купить подожди ещё
again look again let’s see
раз смотри ещё раз давайте мы посмотрим
you start to run away but it turns out
ты начинаешь убегать да оказывается Да
that it’s easier to buy a phone in Estonia a
что телефон проще купить в Эстонии
car it’s easier to buy in Estonia
машину проще купить в Эстонии бензин
it’s easier to buy gasoline in  Estonia, what can you say, that in
проще купить в Эстонии что скажи что в
Russia it is cheaper than in Estonia,
России дешевле чем в Эстонии бензин
gasoline, how much is gasoline, how much does gasoline cost you, half a
бензин сколько у вас ва бензин стоит пол
euro, half a euro, how much gasoline do you use per month,
евро пол евро сколько вы бензина в месяц
liters, now I’ll tell you how much, well, I
литров сейчас скажу сколько вот ну я
drive a little, that is, I fill up somewhere
немного езд то есть заправляюсь где-то
every week, about 2,000  rubles, well, I
каждую неделю где-то на 2.000 руб вот ну
fill up a full tank. Well, I have
полный бак заправляю Вот вот у меня бака
enough tank somewhere. Well, when is there enough when
где-то хватает Ну когда хватает когда
there is not enough for a week, that is, 2,000 multiplied by the
нет на неделю то есть 2.000 умножаем на
tank how many liters how many liters the tank in
бак сколько литров сколько литров бак по
G is somewhere around 48 liters 50 liters tank that is, look
Г где-то 48 л 50 л бак то есть смотри
week 4 weeks then  there is a month you
неделя 4 недели то есть в месяц ты
leave 200
выезжаешь 200
liters, well, you see, you already counted 50 liters
л ну вот видите Вы уже посчитали 50 л
there Why did you count 4 weeks, you can
там Почему вы 4 недели посчитали можеш
better calculate five So you’re just
лучше пять посчитать Так ты же просто ты
not 50 you’re 48 ska not five weeks about Yes, let it
же не 50 ты 48 ска не пять недель про Да
be yes Well, yes, that is,
пускай пускай будет да Ну да то есть
look  200 L Per month, yes, that is, you
смотри 200 Л В месяц да то есть ты
spend uh in money how much is 10,000 rubles
тратишь э в деньгах сколько 10.000 руб
100 100 dollars
100 100 долларов
super yes yes look you Estonia in Estonia
супер да да смотри вы Эстонии в Эстонии
gasoline costs 80 cents I cost
бензин 80 центов стоит я
200 200 l Yes look 200 l I'm sorry
200 200 л Да смотри 200 л я извиняюсь
now let
сечас давай
me see it Of course it's inconvenient I'll be on
вижи мне Конечно неудобно Я буду на
TV  watch let's look at the
телевизоре смотреть давай смотри на
TV in Estonia in Pir at my
телевизор в Эстонии в Пир у меня на
gas station Yes, where do I fill up 80 I don’t
заправке Да где я заправляюсь 80 я не
know in Europe there is a lot of difference
знаю по Европе очень сильно разни ещё
again I say 80 cents yes
раз я говорю 80 центов да
for me 200 0 dollars now look
для ме 200 0 дол теперь смотри
you get it If you compare salaries
ты получается Если сравнивать зарплаты
Yes for me it’s small  share in the salary
Да у меня это маленькая доля в зарплате
And you have a
А у тебя
huge nali
огромная нали
gasoline communal electricity gas this is the
бензин коммуналка электричество газ это
sun obligatory payments and all
ВС обязательные платежи и все
mandatory
обязательны
payments er we saw that in Estonia
платежи ери мы посмотрели что в Эстонии
in Bosch it is three times more than you have in
в ра Боше в три раза больше чем у вас в
your Rostov Yes, if we look at the
вашем Ростове Да если мы смотрим
products gasoline communal it is not in
продукты бензин коммуналка она не есть в
three times more, that is, an Estonian, after
три раза больше то есть у эстонца после
he pays off the utility bill, eats,
того как он выплатит коммуналку покушает
goes to the cinema, he has more
сходит в кино у него остаётся больше
money left than a
денег чем у
Russian, the average cost of gasoline in
россиянина средняя стоимость бензина в
Latvia is lat in
Латвии так лат в 2004
2004. So milk is 1 euro 100
году Так так молоко 1 евро 100
rubles ruble
руб рубля
120 rice eggs eggs Wow  256 rubles for
120 рис яйца яйца Ух ты как 256 руб на
our money 2 euros, that’s almost twice as
наши деньги 2 евро вот почти в два раза
much, not even twice as much, by the way,
больше даже не в два раза больше кстати
look, look, they show that
посмотрел смотрите вот показывают что
the prices in Rostov-on-Don for gasoline are 60
цены в Ростове на Дону на п бензин 60
rubles, this is the ninety-fifth, I said the
руб это девяносто пятый я сказал
ninety-
девяносто
second and not 50 A
второй и не 50 А
58 I tell you  the ninety-fifth told you that
58 я вам я вам девяносто пятый говорил у
we have no one refueling Deno VM
нас дено ВМ никто не
Look if you can
заправляется Смотрите если вы можете
immediately safely take away 6% from them stop stop
сразу смело от них отнимать 6% стоп стоп
question question question What kind of store do you have
вопрос вопрос вопрос Какой у вас магазин
Oh what kind of car do you have If you deno
Ой какой у вас автомобиль Если вы дено
second refuel it look I have
вторым заправляет его смотрите у меня
two cars I
два автомобиля у меня
have
есть Лада кото
I fill up the Lada Koto That is, you specifically
заправляю То есть ты мне специально
told me the very best gasoline in
сказал Самый дей бензин которого в
Europe is not about where for some reason you laughed
Европе не про де почему-то вы засмеялись
You’re hard of hearing, so
Вы плохо слышите так
we can ask the question Where in the
можем во вопрос Где где в странах
European Union countries can you buy the second gasoline? I
Евросоюза дено второй бензин можно
have no idea, wait, wait,
имею подождите подождите на
you’re starting now  you will
деста вы сейчас начинаете будете
look like such a
походить на такого
low-profile So it is No, I
низкопрофильной Так оно и есть Нет я
understand correctly what you are saying to me I said
правильно понимаю что вы мне на Я сказал
I said the cost of ninety-second
я сказал стоимость девяносто второго
gasoline if you didn’t say ninety-
бензина если вы ты не сказал девяносто
second you said gasoline Well, you then
второй ты сказал бензин Ну вы потом
Rewind the video and when you know,
Отмотай видео и когда вы знаете
listen to this moment you please
прослушайте этот момент вы пожалуйста
know  on your live broadcast Tell me I
знаете в своём прямом эфире Скажите я
heard poorly and inattentively lo
плохо слышал и невнимательно ло возможно
perhaps perhaps in short good Let
возможно короче хоро Пусть
Wait pom de gasoline in Estonia
Подождите пом де бензин в Эстонии вот
just for the sake of interest now now now now
просто ради интереса сейчас сейчас сечас
here’s the price of deno second gasoline in Estonia
вот цена на дено второй бензин в Эстонии
interestingly it’s
интересно его там
not there listen Well let’s compare deno five
нет слушайте Ну сравним дено пятый всё
anyway there’s parity  it will be huge, let's
равно там паритет будет огромный давайте
now we will figure out the price of gasoline with the 9th second, no,
сейчас мы с 9 вторым разберёмся цена на
no, we don't, what's the difference?  the
бензин всё нене не мы уже какая разница
price of the second
А сколько в Эстонии стоит дев второй
gasoline is dev, wait, what's the difference as it
бензин Да подождите какая разница как
looks 95 Let's see Since it's for sale,
смотре 95 Посмотрим Раз сним продаётся
that's not the point right Uh-huh And where did
Это ж не суть дело правильно Угу А куда
your Skoda Octavia go sold it and
ваша Skoda Octavia делась продал это и
bought a
купили
Lada No, I bought two
Ладу Нет я купил две
cars from me Dashin and Lada That is, you
машины у меня р Дашин и Лада То есть вы
sold the Skoda Octavia  and bought a Dashine and a
продали Шкоду Октавию и купили Дашин и
Lada, and from one with an aluminum engine,
Ладу да из от с алюминиевым двигателем
then it could be in short that they made it in Kaluga,
то это может короче которые в калуг
hearing it was a copta, it was they in Kaluga who
делали слыша это копту это они калуг
made the pump when I changed the pump, it wasn’t
делали помпу когда я менял помпу её не
original, you couldn’t even order it.
оригинальную даже заказать нельзя было
That’s what Volkswagen did with it.
Вот и то что Volkswagen сделал с этим
In short, it’s just their own  consumers for
Короче это просто своих потребителей для
me, listen, I understand, maybe in short, the one
меня слушай я понял может короче та
that you made in Kaluga, what
которая у вас делалась в Калуге что
really Was cheaper than the Czech one Maybe
реально Была дешевле чем чешская Может
it’s
она
not you’re wrong, it’s VS according to standards
не вы ошибаетесь это ВС по стандартам
This is the KTI plant European was built
Это кти завод Европейский был построен
Note Well, European But especially
Прим Ну так Европейский Но специально
for the Russian market they made it from
для русского рынка делали из алюминия
Latvian EU aluminum  take the prices on Nede with de in
Латвии ЕС взять цены на Неде с де в
Come on de in gasoline look Dep mark cost
Давай де в бензин смотри Деп марке стоил
average deno Second deno
средним дено Второй дено
second privi vni with already groan listen
второй приви вни при уже стони слушайте
different these are different countries I don’t know
отличается это разные страны Я не знаю
what’s in Latvia I’m in Estonia We
что в Латвии Я я в Эстонии Мы про
talked about Estonia Come on Google
Эстонию говорили А ну давай Гугли
Estonia what  in Latvia I thought Come on, de
Эстонии что в Латвия думал Давай де
ninety-second gasoline in Estonia
девяносто второй бензин в Эстонии
How much does it cost already now it’s interesting
Сколько стоит аж аж теперь интересно
because Apparently Estonia is
потому что Судя по всему Эстония - это
some kind of oasis in Europe everywhere
какой-то оазис в Европе везде ещё раз
I say again, find me how much it costs you said
говорю найди мне сколько стоит ты сказал
you have ninety-second gasoline so much
у вас девяносто второй бензин столько
it costs find how much  it costs in
это стоит найди сколько он стоит в
Estonia for pennies they are giving away Estonia
Эстонии за копейки раздают Эстонию
now I will write Estonia the deno of the second gasoline
сейчас напишу Эстония дено второй бензин
in Estonia Find How much Yes wait
в Эстонии Найди Почём Да подождите
ninety-fifth We are comparing let’s
девяносто пятый Мы же сравниваем давай
first with the ninety-second You opened the
сначала с девяносто второго Ты же открыл
deno you said ninety-second Let’s
дено вй ты сказал девяносто второй Давай
open the ninety-second you know these
открой девяносто второй знаете вот такие
children’s ones, that is, yes  and we compare
детские то есть да а сравниваем паритет
price parity question question why while you are looking
цен вопрос вопрос почему пока вы ищете
Yes question Why in Estonia there is no ninety-
Да вопрос Почему в Эстонии нет девяносто
second gasoline and there is no Lada car and
второго бензина и нет машины Лада ётся и
I won’t find de vro In short for us Dep We
я не найду де вро Короче нам Деп Мы же
also go through Let’s not first on
также пройти Давайте Не сначала по
ninety-second or
девяносто втором или
it turns out listen you are not you now
получается слушайте вы сейчас не вы
they named look, you named the most expensive
назвали смотрите Вы назвали самый чный
gasoline in Russia, yes, here it costs 40, but
бензин в России да у нас он стоит 40 да
it turns out that there is no such gasoline in the
оказывается такого бензина нету в
European Union. And it turns out that
Евросоюзе Да и оказывается что такие
cars like yours are not available in the European Union. I
машин как у вас нет в Евросоюзе я
understand correctly
правильно понимаю
what type of
каких типа
Lada is an excellent car, you don’t have any,
Лады отличная машина у вас никакой
by the way, in Estonia, you don’t have any  there are no Estonians
кстати в Эстонии никакой у эстонцев нет
Masha,
Маши
we buy ours, we buy a normal European
свои мы покупаем нормальный Европейский
Volvo, we buy business, you don’t
Volvo покупаем дело вас никакой
understand, it’s not yours What kind of car do you have?
понимаете не ваше коро Какая у вас
Russian Lada Vesta Lada Granta
машина Российская Лада Веста Лада Гранта
Niva So wait, Since it’s Russian,
Нива Так подожди Так как это российский
if you look at it, you say yes, that they
если смотрите вы говорите да что они из
are made from sticks Yes, I didn’t say that, you
палок делаются Да я не говорил это вы
say it  I understand How many airbags do you own?
говорите Поня Сколько подушек
What How many airbags are there in the
Владе что Сколько подушек безопасности в
Lada? I have two
Ладе две У меня две
questions: Lada Vesta How much is the price,
вопрос Лада Веста Сколько стоит цена
pay attention, how much does your Lada Vesta cost,
внимайте сколько стоит Лада Веста ваша
I want to see Wait, let's
вот я хочу посмотреть Подождите Давайте
see the prices, how much does your Lada Vesta cost, look?
смотрите Я сейчас так я смотрите Я
now
сейчас гуглю Давай прямо сейчас
wait wait 18,000 dollars for
подождите подождите 18.000 долларов на
gasoline in Estonia Wait Stop stop stop
бензин в Эстонии Подожди Стоп стоп стоп
again Lada vesta costs 1n 00 Answer the
ещё раз Лада vesta стоит 1н 00 Ответьте
question why you la so I'm now
на вопрос почему вы ла так я сейчас я
googling Lada Vesta Lada Vesta
гуглю Ладу весту Лада Веста
price
цена
So you wait min Now we'll
Так ты так подожди мин Сейчас мы
see How much is really like that
посмотрим Сколько реально так
Rostov Yes 16  million rubles oh 1,600 1,800 it
Ростов Да 16 млн рубле ой 1 600 1.800
turns out that your Lada Vesta costs 18,000
получается у вас Лада Веста стоит 18.000
dollars, I understood correctly Well, yes,
долларов я правильно понял Ну да
the question is for the price of this, what can you buy?
вопрос за цену этого что можно купить
What kind of car in the
Какую машину в
EU I have no idea, I understand Why are you
ЕС Понятия не имею понял А зачем вы
opening If you have no idea
открываете Если вы не имеете понятия
Listen, wait, wait What to wait,
Слушай подождите подождите Что ждать
why are you  opened you have no idea
зачем вы открыли вы не имеете понятия
Look, I’m a deputy Yes, here we can in
Смотри я депутат Да вот мы можем в
Estonia for 18 euros Yes and for 18
Эстонии за 18 штук евро Да и за 18 штук
dollars Yes, buy a cool imported
долларов Да купить классную импортную
car Yes, you buy for 18,000 dollars and it
машину Да вы за 18000 долларов покупаете
drives me you want to look again
н ездит на меня вы хоте ня ещ раз смотри
Why yours Explain why yours
Почему ваши Объясните почему ваши
deputies like ours Yes, they don’t drive a
депутаты такие как наши Да не ездят на
Lada Why don’t your deputies drive a
Ладе Почему ваши депутаты не ездят на
Lada Estonian wanted to deceive
Ладе обмануть хотела Эстонская
again I’m telling you you found ninety-
ещё раз я тебе говорю ты нашёл девяносто
second gasoline While you’re looking I’ll
второй бензин Пока ищешь Я тебе буду
continue to dip you in yours In short,
дальше макать тебя в твои Короче так вот
tell me
скажи мне
why your deputies drive ours
Почему ваши депутаты ездят на наших
European Union cars
евросоюзом машинах
why and why do you see it like that already
почему а почему ты так видишь у тебя уже
go and wait
поди подожди
you because yes look people Yes we I
ты потому что да смотрите люди Да мы я
will tell all my voters that they are Russian
всем своим избирателям скажу что русские
They hate us Estonians yes they
они Они ненавидят нас эстонцев да они
live
живут
in yes
в да
and they don’t want to live normally they live with such a
и не хотят жить нормально живут с таким
minimum wage  190 of these
минимальной заработной платой 190 этих
dollars Yes, here I live That's it,
долларов Да вот я живу Вот так
you're in the hotel Well, you're in the hotel
вот это ты в гостинице Ну ты в гостинице
I'm No, this is my apartment This is the
я по Нет это моя квартира Это
hotel Hotel hammer
гостиница Гостиница забивай
in residential complex white angel show show show
забивай ЖК бело ангел к покажи покажи
your apartment show if this is your
свою квартиру покажи если это твоя
apartment Show that this is not a
квартира Покажи что это не
hotel
гостиница
Show enough of those  Hotel
Покажи достаточно те Гостиничный
TV Well, this is a hotel, you can see it, look,
телевизор Ну это гостиница видно смотри
put it on the Internet Show the corridor,
забивай в интернете Покажи коридор
show it, show it in the corridor in the hotel at the
покажи покажи в коридоре в гостинице при
entrances there is a description Show the sign
входах есть описание Покажи щиток Сейчас
Now now I'm so let's
сейчас я давай так
give things I just don't want
давай вещи я просто не хочу личную жизнь
to show my personal life I don't show show
свою показывать не показываю покажи
just that this is not a
просто что это не
hotel my things are  things they
гостиница вещи мои это вещи они в
may not be in the hotel Show at the
гостинице могут лежать не Покажи при
entrance with look and those at the Hotel but
входе с смотри а а те по Гостиничный но
show the entrance Show, look, I
покажи подъезд Покажи смотри я же тебе
can offer you an easy way to check whether
могу предлагаю простой способ проверить
the hotel is or
гостиница или
not this is a house, you won’t confuse the residential complex Bela angel
нет это дом не перепутаешь ЖК Белы ангел
ra you I won’t No again  Look at
ра ты это я не буду Нет с ещё раз Смотри
these pictures on the Internet, it’s all nonsense
это картинки в интернете это всё брехня
You show me for real Show me the corridor that
Ты мне покажи реально Покажи коридор что
this is a residential corridor and not
это коридор жилой а не
Ada And in the hotel It’s a long one, it’s a
Аде А в гостини Вот она длинная идт
corridor like that and that’s it Well okay
коридор типа и вс Ну хорошо
Dava Well I don’t want a mess somewhere I have
Дава Ну я не хочу где-то бардак у меня
Tom
Том
show Zavra the maid will come  ubert
показывать Завра горничная придёт уберт
in hotels she cleans
в гостиницах она убирает
Neva come on show me the corridor this is not
Нева давай покажи коридор это не
a hotel
Гостиничный
measles tunnel this is in hotels only
кори тоннель такой это в гостиницах толь
in houses how many rooms do you have here on How many
в дома сколько у вас комнат тут на
rooms are there on a floor in a
Сколько тут комнат на этаже в
hotel look What is the point you don’t
гостинице смотри В чём суть ты ж не
want You know that you are the floor Wait
хочешь Ты знаешь что ты пол Подожди
Look you  showed the Hotel corridor,
Смотри ты показал Гостиничный коридор
this is what it’s like for normal residential
вот он такой для нормально жилые
complexes don’t do this, you know, like
комплексы не делают такой знаешь как
catacombs In short, it’s just a tunnel And listen,
катакомбы Короче просто тоннель А слушай
let’s do this Well,
ну давай так
I kept receipts for utilities in the hotel.
Ну я в гостинице хранил квитанции по
I don’t see that these are receipts.
коммуналке Я не вижу что это квитанции
I can’t see there,
мне не видно там
well, there are some papers. I’m in the hotel.
хорошо какие-то бумаги Я в гостинице
I’ll
буду
bury an album with photographs Well, yes, you
хоронить альбом с фотографиями Ну да ты
take it I’m in a hotel I
его возишь Я в гостини Я в гостинице
’ll keep, say, a photo of my daughter in a hotel
буду хранить допустим фото своей дочки
Well, perhaps your wife kicked you out of the
ну тебя возможно тебя жена выгнала из
house and you settled in a hotel on
дома и ты же в гостинице поселился на
Ned I live alone, first of all, I live alone I’m
Неде Я живу один я во-первых живу один я
divorced  And secondly, you can search on the
в разводе А во-вторых ты можешь забить в
Internet for the Bel Angel Rostov residential complex. You will need it and
интернете ЖК бел ангел Ростов надону и
you will see the landscapes that I showed you. I
ты увидишь пейзажи который тебе показал
won’t. Look, it’s not a hotel, it’s not guests.
не буду Смотри не гостиница не это гости
Well, look, I saw the corridor. Okay,
Ну смотри я видел коридор Хорошо давай
so look, look, I’m suggesting to you. Why are
так смотри смотри я тебе предлагаю Зачем
you guessing at your place?  with this hand,
ты гадаешь у тебя у тебя под рукой этот
this is you. When you need to
вот это ты Когда надо тебе что-то
look at something, you are like knock-knock-knock
поглядеть ты такой тук-тук-тук
quickly. I suggest to you. Just kill
быстренько Я тебе предлагаю Просто забей
me, angel, I’ll show you again, I’ll show you the pictures.
л ангел я тебе ещё раз покажу я картинки
I don’t understand from these views, you understand,
Я не пойму по этим видам понимаешь к
Bela, and you’ll understand everything, I’m wrong there.
бела ан ты всё поймёшь там мне ошибиться
impossible No again show me wrong
невозможно Нет ещё раз покажи ошибиться
impossible White angel there and the entrances
невозможно Белый ангел там и подъезды
photos are all there no look if If
фотографии всё есть нет смотри если Ели
you have a Hotel how many apartments do you have on the floor
у тебя Гостиница сколько у тебя на этаже
now I’ll tell you 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 in
квартир сейчас скажу 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 во
apartments there were more there were 10 pieces there were
квартир там больше было там штук 10 было
These are rooms hotel rooms  8 10
Это комнаты гостиничные номера 8 10
in short, well, it’s the same Show Okay,
короче ну это такое же Покажи Хорошо
show me the meter meters for only 10
покажи счётчики счётчиков только на 10
electric apartments Listen, well, I have one o By
электрических Слушай ну у меня оди о
the way, I have
Кстати у меня
a meter Well, first of all, I’ll show you now
счётчик Ну во-первых я тебе сейчас
the water meters, don’t Show me how many
счётчики водяные не Покажи сколько
electric meters Yes, there are actually two
электрические Да здесь вообще здесь две
sections here, four Here  and there are four people there, it
секции четыре Здесь и там четыре такое
feels like there are no people, it’s
ощущение что людей нету это гостиница
some kind of hotel where people are
какая-то где люди
all yes. Listen, you won’t please me, I’m
все да Слушай Тебе не угодишь я те
telling you in no uncertain terms. Let him say that this is not a hotel,
че Пусть он скажет что это не гостиница
but say that it’s a residential complex, listen, no, you
а скажет что это ЖК слушай Нет ты очень
want a lot, I’m the simplest option.
много хочешь я те пре простой вариант
Take a knock on your neighbors if they are
Возьми постучись к соседям если это
neighbors you should know them if it’s not
соседи ты должен их знать если это не
that there are no such houses in Estonia Look you
что в Эстонии таких домов нет Смотри ты
really you really live in a hotel now
реально ты реально в гостинице сейчас
you live in a hotel so you
живёшь ты живёшь в гостинице поэтому ты
don’t know the state Apparently you don’t
не знаешь состо Судя по всему небогато
live well that’s why it’s not a shock for you
живёте вот поэтому для тебя это шок не
show me again, show me, what are there
ещ раз покажи мне покажи мне Да что там
real people? This is
реальные люди Это
a hotel, show me your toilet, why should I
гостиница показывай свой унитаз зачем я
show my house somehow? In short,
показывать свою хату каким-то Короче
come on, show me the toilet, I’ll show you anything,
давай вот покажеш унитаз покажу всё что
look, I’m not like you, to
угодно смотри я же не такой как ты чтоб
climb, show your house,
лазить показывать свою хату слу
nothing, nothing, Dude  you're below
Да ничего ничего Чувак ты себя ниже
the plinth
плинтуса
Come on, subscribe to my Telegram right
Давай подпишись на мий Telegram прямо
now autumn, and for now
зараз осень а пок
it's even more and more important YouTube taking us
це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня нас
through SRR to your ban and even more videos I
через срр в твый бан и дуже багато вдео
don't show people at the moment I don't show
не показую людям вчасно не показуе
information about streams For this reason,
информация про стрими Тому для того щоб
we need Mali to write an operational link
ми Мали оперативный звязок пишиться
directly  zazar and while there in telegra okm
прямо зараз а пок там в телегра окм
video schetezh va and korisna information and
видео ще теж ва и корисна информация и
mipon z you trima sing
ми пон з вами трима пой
operational connection
оперативный звязок
nezalezhno in togo chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
subscribe L
подпишись L